Guide to the Records of the New York University Sesquicentennial Celebration MC.7
New York University Archives
Records of the New York University Sesquicentennial Celebration
1965-1982
1979-1981
New York University Archives
New York University. Sesquicentennial Committee
MC.7
1.5 Linear Feet
Historical Note
In 1981 New York University celebrated the 150th anniversary of its founding with a year-long celebration centering on the theme of The Role of the Urban University and the Future of the Cities. The stated purpose of the commemoration was to celebrate the image, role and impact of NYU in the context of New York City, reach out to aspects of the community, and increase awareness of the university's academic strengths.
The events kicked off on October 13 with the official proclamation of New York University Week by Mayor Ed Koch and continued throughout the academic year until commencement in June of 1982. Dr. John Brademas's inauguration as the University's 13th president on October 14 was incorporated into the celebration. Another major event came with the dedication of the Coles Sports Center on October 24.
Every University school offered symposia, lectures, and other sesquicentennial events throughout the academic year. There were also musical and dance performances, guided walking tours, special exhibits at the Grey Art Gallery, and a series of television and radio specials about NYU and its history.
Scope and Contents Note
This collection contains minutes of Sesquicentennial committee meetings, correspondence, lists, calendars of events, printed materials, budget-related material, and promotional and historical material drafted for the commemoration. Some materials used in the planning of the Sesquicentennial in the collection date prior to 1978.
The collection recounts the development of the celebration from early planning in 1978 to commencement exercises in 1982. It documents the creation of the Advisory and Executive Committees, alumni involvement, the study of other universities' anniversary celebrations, and the planning, organization, marketing, and branding of the events throughout the NYU community. Also included are budget and fundraising reports. Overall, the collection provides a portrait of the organization of a major anniversary celebration.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Related Materials
Additional ephemera from the Sesquicentennial, committee minutes and published materials relating to the events can be found at the University Archives in MC 7 (Sesquicentennial Celebration Collection). Related material can also be found in the biographic file of Dr. John Brademas.
Restrictions
Access to some materials in this collection may be restricted due to personal information. Contact the University Archivist for more information.
Reports.; Minutes (administrative records); Universities and Colleges -- Alumni and alumnae.; Brochures.; Universities and colleges |x Public relations.; Public relations.; Budgets.; Pamphlets.; Mailing lists.; Membership lists.; Registers (lists).; New York University. School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions; New York University. School of Law; New York University. School of Continuing Education; New York University; Levine, Naomi B., 1923-; Tisch School of the Arts; University of Southern California; New York University. College of Dentistry; New York University. Graduate School of Business Administration; Gallatin Associates; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science; Grey Art Gallery & Study Center; Brademas, John, 1927-2016; New York University -- Centennial celebrations, etc.
- Series I: Subject Files, 1979-1981
  - Advisory Committee, 1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alumni, 1978-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bennett, Ivan, 1979-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Budget, 1979-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Business and Public Administration, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Calendar, Engagement, 1980-1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Creative Services, 1979-1981, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dental School, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee, 1979, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences, 1979, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gallatin Associates, 1978-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1976, circa 1978, circa 1979, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Grey Art Gallery, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Law School, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Levine, Naomi, 1979-1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Marketing, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Organization, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Programs and Services of NYU, circa 1981-1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Proposal for, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Salomon Brothers Center, circa 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - School of Continuing Education, circa 1979, 1980, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - SEHNAP, 1979, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - School of the Arts, Tisch, 1977, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Silverman, Herbert R., 1979-1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Student Organization Listing, circa 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Students, Meetings with, 1979-1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Students, Financial Aid, circa 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Trustees, circa 1965-1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - University of Southern California, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Urban Studies Center, 1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)